Guide to the William C. Lynch Dennis Brain Collection ARS.0138
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Compact Discs, circa 1936-2011; 155 discs 123 CD-Rs; 32 compact discs
  - Commercial recordings, circa 1939-1997; 38 items 28 compact discs; 10 CD-Rs
    - Britten: Serenade, 1944 May - October; 1 compact disc; London, 4259962 (Audio 3, Disc 8)
      Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Serenade, tenor, horn, string orchestra, op. 31. Pears, Peter, Sir, tenor. Boyd Neel London String Orchestra; Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976, conductor. Decca Studios. 1944 May 25; 1944 October 8.
    - Dennis Brain: his early recordings (1939-1946), 1 compact disc; Grammofono 2000, AB78729 (Audio 3, Disc 9)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1946 March 27.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, horn, piano, op. 17, F major. Matthews, Denis, piano. 1944 February.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 334, D major. Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, horn. Léner Quartet. 1939 February 16.
    - Strauss (Richard), 1953-1954; 1 compact disc; EMI Classics, 5674952 (Audio 3, Disc 10)
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Letzte Lieder. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Ackermann, Otto, 1909-1960, conductor. 1953 September 25.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Capriccio. Selections. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Ackermann, Otto, 1909-1960, conductor. 1953 September 26.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Arabella. Selections. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Matačić, Lovro von, conductor.
    - Britten the performer, 1956 June 21; 1 compact disc; BBC, BBCB80142 (Audio 3, Disc 11)
      Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Canticle, no. 2. Pears, Peter, Sir, tenor. Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976, piano. Aldeburgh Church. 1956 June 21.
    - Beethoven, Dukas, Marais, Mozart, and Brahms, 1957 February-August; 1 compact disc; BBC, BBCL40482 (Audio 3, Disc 12)
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, op. 16, E♭ major. Dennis Brain Wind Ensemble. User Hall, Edinburgh. 1957 August 24.
      Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Villanelle, horn, piano. Usher Hall, Edinburgh. 1957 August 24.
      Marais, Marin, 1656-1728. Pièces de violes, 4e livre. 1ère partie. Suitte, no. 5. Basque. Parry, Wilfrid, piano. Usher Hall, Edinburgh. 1957 August 24.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, horn, violin, violas, cello, K. 407, E♭ major. English String Quartet. BBC Studios, London (England). 1957 February 18.
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 40, E♭ major. Salpeter, Max, violin. Preedy, Cyril, piano. BBC Studios, London (England). 1957 February 15.
    - Beethoven, Schubert, Mozart, Haydn, Cooke, Ibert, and Milhaud. Also included, The Early Horn, 1953-1957; 1 compact disc; BBC, BBCL40662 (Audio 3, Disc 13)
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sextets, horns (2), strings, op. 81b, E♭major. Civil, Alan, horn. English String Quartet. BBC Studios, London (England). 18 February 1957.
      Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Auf dem Strom. Pears, Peter, Sir, tenor. Mewton-Wood, Noel, 1922-1953, piano. BBC Studios, London (England). 1953 January 28.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 270, B♭ major. Malcolm, George, 1917-1997, piano. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. BBC Studios, London (England). 1957 July 22.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Concertos, horn, orchestra, H. VIId, 3, D major. BBC Midland Orchestra; Wurmser, Leo, conductor. BBC Studios, London (England). 1957 July 22.
      Cooke, Arnold, 1906-2005. Arioso and Scherzo. Carter Trio. Lempfert, Marjorie, 1921-1992, viola. BBC Studios, London (England). 1957 March 1.
      Ibert, Jacques, 1890-1962. Pièces brèves. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. BBC Studios, London (England). 1957 July 22.
      Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974. Cheminée du roi René. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. BBC Studios, London (England). 1955 June 22.
      Tracklisting.
      The Early Horn. Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, demonstrates the sounds and playing techniques of different horns. 1955 July 23.
    - Beethoven, Jacob, Hindemith, and Vinter, 1953-1957; 1 compact disc; BBC, BBCL41642 (Audio 3, Disc 14)
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, op. 16, E♭ major. Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976, piano. James, Cecil, 1913-1999, bassoon. Waters, Stephen, clarinet. Brain, Leonard, 1915-1975, oboe. Aldeburgh Festival of Music and the Arts. 1955 June 22.
      Jacob, Gordon, 1895-1984. Concertos, horn, string orchestra. James, Cecil, 1913-1999, bassoon. Waters, Stephen, clarinet. Brain, Leonard, 1915-1975, oboe. Morris, Gareth, flute. Malcolm, George, 1917-1997, piano. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. BBC Studios, London (England). 1957 July 22.
      Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Concertos, horn, orchestra. Mewton-Wood, Noel, 1922-1953, piano. BBC Studios, London (England). 1953 January 28.
      Vinter, Gilbert. Hunter's moon. BBC Concert Orchestra; Tausky, Vilem. conductor. BBC Studios, London (England). 1957 June 16.
    - Mozart, Britten, Schumann, Milhaud, and Fricker, 1953-1957; 1 compact disc; BBC, BBCL41622 (Audio 3, Disc 15)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 447, E♭major. BBC Symphony Orchestra; Sargent, Malcolm, Sir, 1895-1967, conductor. Royal Albert Hall (London, England). 1953 July 30.
      Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Serenade, tenor, horn, string orchestra, op. 31. Pears, Peter, Sir, tenor. BBC Symphony Orchestra; Hollingsworth, John, 1916-1963, conductor. Royal Albert Hall (London, England). 1953 July 30.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 270, B♭ major. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. BBC Studios, London (England). 1956 June 19.
      Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Adagio und Allegro, horn, piano, op. 70, A♭ major. Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976, piano. Aldeburgh Church. Aldeburgh Festival of Music and the Arts. 1956 June 21.
      Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974. Cheminée du roi René. Chasse á Valabre. BBC Studios, London (England). 1956 June 19.
      Fricker, Peter Racine, 1920-1990. Quintet, winds, op. 5. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. Freemason's Hall, Edinburgh (Scotland). Edinburgh International Festival. 1957 August 24.
    - Joan Sutherland: recitals, 1956 December 17; 1 compact disc; Bellavoce, BLV107001 (Audio 3, Disc 16)
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Si ti perdo amata sposa. Goldsborough Orchestra; Mackerras, Charles, 1925-2010, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation. 1956 December 17.
    - Strauss (Richard) and Hindemith, undated; 1 compact disc; EMI, CDC7478342 (Audio 3, Disc 17)
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 1, op. 11, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Sawallisch, Wolfgang, 1923-2013, conductor.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 2, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Sawallisch, Wolfgang, 1923-2013, conductor.
      Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Concertos, horn, orchestra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963, conductor.
    - Robert Inglez and his orchestra: come closer to me, 1946-1948; 1 compact disc; Vocalion, CDEA6062. (Audio 3, Disc 18)
      Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, is not credited on this recording. However, a note accompanying the item states that the reason for its inclusion is that Brain was known to have been playing with Inglez, Roberto during the time in question, 1946-1948, and that the horn style demonstrated is reminiscent of Brain's and therefore thought to be him.
      Inglez, Roberto. Roberto Inglez Orchestra.
      Savoy Hotel (London, England). 1946-1948.
    - Mozart Horn Concertos, 1953; 1 compact disc; EMI, CDH7610132 (Audio 3, Disc 19)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1953.
    - Dennis and Aubrey Brain: Mozart, 1939-1946; 1 compact disc; EMI Classics, CDH7641982. (Audio 3, Disc 20)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 447, E♭ major. Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, horn. BBC Symphony Orchestra; Boult, Adrian, 1889-1983, conductor. Colston Hall, Bristol (England). 1940 April 10.
    - Bob Sharples: dimension in sound; contrasts in hi-fi, circa 1958; 2 compact discs; Vocalion, CDLK4169. (Audio 3, Disc 21)
      Sharples, Bob. Sympathy.
    - Geraldo and his orchestra, 1942; 1 CD-R; Digitized copy of Parlophone, F1938. (Audio 3, Disc 22)
      Where in the world. Chamber, Len, vocalist. 1942.
    - Dennis Brain: Mozart, Beethoven, and Strauss (Richard), 1943-1947; 1 compact disc; Pearl, GEM0026. (Audio 23, Disc 23)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, horn, violin, violas, cello, K. 407, E♭ major. Griller String Quartet. 1944 October 6; 1944 October 25.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, horn, piano, op. 17, F major. Matthews, Denis, piano. 1944 February 21.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 447, E♭ major. Hallé Orchestra; Turner, Laurence, conductor. 1943 June 21.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 1, op. 11, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1947 May 21.
    - The golden age of light music - volume two., 1942; 1 compact disc; Guild, GLCD5135. Original publication: HMV, RAF7. (Audio 3, Disc 24)
      Coates, Eric, 1886-1957. Over to you. Royal Air Force Orchestra. O'Donnell, R.P, conductor. 1942.
      Coates, Eric, 1886-1957. Song of loyalty. Royal Air Force Orchestra. O'Donnell, R.P, conductor. 1942.
    - Grosse Hornisten volume two: Dennis Brain, rare radio recordings, 1948-1956; 1 compact disc; Hans Pizka Edition, HPECD02. (Audio 3, Disc 25)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Südwestfunk (Baden-Baden, Germany). Orchester; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963, conductor. Kursaal, Baden-Baden (Germany).1948
      Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Sonatas, horn, piano (1939). Hansen, Conrad, piano. 1951.
      Danzi, Franz, 1763-1826. Concertos, horn, orchestra, P. 239, E major. Kurpfälzisches Kammer-Orchester; Bodart, Eugen, 1905-1981, conductor. 1955.
      Schoeck, Othmar, 1886-1957. Concertos, horn, string orchestra, op. 65. Basler Kammerorchester; Sacher, Paul, 1906-1999, conductor. 1956.
    - Brain in the orchestra, 1951-1953; 1 compact disc; Opus Kura, OPK7016. (Audio 3, Disc 26)
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Symphonies, no. 6, op. 68, F major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1953.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Symphonies, no. 8, op. 93, F major. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1951.
    - Strauss (Richard), 1947 May 21; 1 compact disc; Testament, SBT1009. (Audio 3, Disc 27)
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 1, op. 11, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1947 May 21.
    - Guido Cantelli conducts Wagner and Brahms, 1947-1951; 1 compact disc; Testament, SBT1012. (Audio 3, Disc 28)
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. 2. Aufzug. 2. Szenen. Mässig bewegt. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1947 May 14.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Siegfried-Idyll. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1951 October 16.
    - Nathan Milstein: Goldmark Violin Concerto (1), Lalo Symphonie espagnole, 1957 July 2-4; 1 CD-R; Testament, SBT1047. (Audio 3, Disc 29)
      Goldmark, Karl, 1830-1915. Violin Concerto No.1 in A minor, Op.28. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1957 July 2-4. Includes unpublished session takes.
    - Walter Gieseking: Philharmonia Wind Quartet, 1953-1955; 1 compact disc; Testament, SBT1091. (Audio 3, Disc 30)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, K. 452, E♭ major. Gieseking, Walter, 1895-1956, piano. Philharmonia Wind Quartet. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1955 April 15-16.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, op. 16, E♭ major. Gieseking, Walter, 1895-1956, piano. Philharmonia Wind Quartet. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1955 April 15-16.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sinfonie concertanti, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, orchestra, K. Anh. 9, E♭ major. Sutcliffe, Sidney, oboe. Walton, Bernard (Clarinetist), clarinet. James, Cecil, 1913-1999, bassoon. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1953 November 17-18.
    - Wilhelm Furtwangler: Strauss (Richard) and Wagner, 1950 May 22; 1 compact disc; Testament, SBT1410. (Audio 3, Disc 31)
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Letzte Lieder. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954, conductor.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. Selections. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954, conductor.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Selections. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954, conductor.
      Recording locations and dates
      Royal Albert Hall (London, England). 1950 May 22.
    - The art of Dennis Brain, 1944-1953; 1 CD-R; Digitized copy of Seraphim, 60040. (Audio 2, Disc 180)
      Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Villanelle, horn, piano. Moore, Gerald, 1899-1987, piano. 1952 April.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, horn, piano, op. 17, F major. Matthews, Denis, Piano. 1944 February.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 289, E♭ major. Dennis Brain Wind Ensemble. 1952 November.
      Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Adagio und Allegro, horn, piano, op. 70, A♭ major. Moore, Gerald, 1899-1987, piano. 1952 April.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 31, D major. Morris, Gareth, flute. Sanders, Neill. horn. Chapman, Edmund, horn. Cursue, Alfred, horn. Westrup, J. A. (Jack Allan), 1904-1975, conductor. 1952 September.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1946 March.
    - The art of Dennis Brain vol.2, circa 1953-1957; 1 CD-R; Digitized copy of Seraphim, 60073. (Audio 2, Disc 181)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, K. 452, E♭ major. Dennis Brain Wind Ensemble. Horsley, Colin, piano.
      Berkeley, Lennox, 1903-1989. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 44. Horsley, Colin, piano. Parikian, Manoug, violin.
    - The art of Dennis Brain vol.3, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; Digitized copy of Seraphim, 60169. (Audio 2, Disc 182)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 270, B♭ major. Dennis Brain Ensemble.
      Ibert, Jacques, 1890-1962. Pièces brèves. Dennis Brain Ensemble.
      Jacob, Gordon, 1895-1984. Sextet, piano, flute, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon. Dennis Brain Ensemble.
- Photographs, circa 1921-1957; 2 folders (Box 12)
  Photocopies and full quality prints featuring Brain and members of his family. Images include publicity shots, performance and touring images, and various personal photographs from his childhood and later family life. Also included are photographs of Brain's car following his fatal car accident in 1957 and an image of his gravestone in Hampstead Cemetery, London, England.
- Research materials, circa 1953-2012; 14 folders
  Research materials acquired and created by authors Lynch, Willlam C., 1943-, and Gamble, Stephen, 1963-, during the writing of Dennis Brain: a life in music.
  - Sotheby's auction of Dennis Brain materials, 1996-2002; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Photocopies of a Sotheby's auction catalog for an auction on 1996 December 6 that featured hundreds of published scores from Dennis Brain's personal library, as well as about a dozen manuscript scores written for him. Also included are copies of an article from The Jongleaur, newsletter of the Mills Music Library at University of Wisconsin - Madison, that describes the library's interest in obtaining the collection.
  - Interviews with Los Angeles horn players, circa 1997-2004; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Transcribed interviews with Hilliard, Howard; Hyde, George; Decker, James; Cave, Jack; Robinson, Gale; De Rosa, Vincent.
  - Dennis Brain: a celebration. Royal Academy of Music 11-15-2002, 2002 November 11; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Assorted ephemera relating to a day long celebration of Brain at the Royal Academy of Music (London, England: 1822- ), on 2002 November 15. Features flyers, posters, programs, and a notable attendees list.
  - Dennis Brain broadcast inventory, undated; 1 folder (Box 11)
    A copy of an incomplete inventory of radio broadcast times from the BBC Written Archives. Features information on actual broadcasts and also some that were planned but never went ahead. Also features select correspondence between Essex, Kenneth, 1943-1962 and various personnel at BBC Radio.
  - Dennis Brain tours, undated; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Research notes relating to various tours Brain undertook during his career.
  - London Baroque Ensemble; London Mozart Players, 2003; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Email correspondence pertaining to the London Baroque Ensemble and London Mozart Players.
  - Alfred Brain, circa 1999; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Research materials relating to Alfred Brain. Includes an interview with Howard Hilliard from 1999 November, along with various reproductions of photographs of Brain.
  - Aubrey Brain, circa 1953-2003; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Research materials relating to Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955. Includes various articles and email correspondence.
  - Dennis Brain's appearance on the Today Show, circa 2002-2003; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Research materials and email correspondence pertaining to Brain's appearance on the Today Show, circa October 1955, hosted at the time by Garroway, Dave, 1913-1982.
  - Dennis Brain articles, circa 1950-2011; 1 folder (Box 11)
    Scope and content
    Photocopies of various published articles relating to Brain, both during his lifetime and since.
  - Research notes, circa 2003-2011; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - International Horn Society briefing: W. Lynch, San Francisco, circa 2011; 1 folder 15 computer files
    Materials related to a presentation given by Lynch, William C., 1943-, at the 43rd International Horn Symposium, held at San Francisco State University in June 2011. The International Horn Symposium series is curated by the International Horn Society.
  - Dennis Brain book collection files, circa 2009-2012; 1 folder 1002 computer files
    Various text documents, email correspondence, images and MP3 audio files created or collated during the writing of Dennis Brain: a life in music.
  - Dennis Brain on record: a comprehensive discography of his solo, chamber, and orchestral recordings, 2011; 1 computer file PDF file; Marshall, Robert Lewis
  - Kaoru Chiba: student of Dennis Brain, circa 2006-2012; 1 folder 13 computer files
    Text documents and images relating to Brain's student, Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008.
  - Text to Brahms Part Songs, CD 102, 2012; 1 computer file PDF file
    English translation of Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Gesänge, women's voices, horns (2), harp, op. 17. See CD 102, Box 1.
- Shellac discs, 1934-1949; 10 12" shellac discs
  Dennis Brain's involvement in these performances is assumed and therefore his name is not stated in the performance listings unless his involvement was other than that of hornist. Additionally, a number of recordings listed here feature Dennis Brain's father, Aubrey Brain.
  - Strauss (Richard), 1934 March 5; 2 12" shellac discs; His Masters Voice. Sides 1 and 2; D.B.2187 (disc number); 32-4462 (side number), 32-4463 (side number); 2B6811 / 2 (matrix number / take number), 2B6812 (matrix number / take number). Sides 3 and 4; D.B.2188 (disc number); 32-4464 (side number), 32-4465 (side number); 2B6813/1 (matrix number / take number), 2B6814/2 (matrix number / take number). (Audio 8, Disc 1, Disc 2)
    Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Till Eulenspiegels lustige Streiche. BBC Symphony Orchestra; Busch, Fritz, 1890-1951, conductor. 1934 March 5. Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, features in his role as principal horn for the BBC Symphony Orchestra.
  - Mozart, 1940 April 9; 2 12" shellac discs; His Masters Voice. Sides 1 and 2; DB3973 (disc number); 2EA8663 / 3(matrix number / take number), 2EA8664 / 1 (matrix number / take number). Sides 3 and 4; DB3974 (disc number); 2EA8665 / 2 (matrix number / take number), 2EA8666 / 2 (matrix number / take number). (Audio 8, Disc 3, Disc 4)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 447, E♭ major. Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, horn. BBC Symphony Orchestra; Boult, Adrian, 1889-1983, conductor. Bristol, Colston Hall.1940 April 9.
  - Handel, 1949 December 28; 1 12" shellac disc; Parlophone. R. 20581 (disc number); CXE12797 (matrix number, side 1), CXE12798 (matrix number, side 2). (Audio 8, Disc 5)
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Overture (suite) in C major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1949 December 28.
  - Weber, 1946 March 12; 1 12" shellac disc; Columbia. DX1244 (disc number); CAX9473 (matrix number, side 1), CAX9474 (matrix number, side 2). (Audio 8, Disc 6)
    Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826. Freischütz. Ouverture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1946 March 12.
  - Mozart, 1944 October 6; 1 12" shellac disc; Decca. K1139 (disc number); AR8744 (matrix number, side A), AR8745 (matrix number, side B). (Audio 8, Disc 7)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, horn, violin, violas, cello, K. 407, E♭ major. Griller, Sidney, violin. Burton, Philip, violin. Gilbert, Max, violin. Hampton, Colin, 1911-1996, cello. 1944 October 6.
  - Bach, 1945-1946; 3 12" shellac discs; Decca. Sides 1 and 2; K1541 (disc number); AR9523 (matrix number, side 1), AR9524 (matrix number, side 2). Sides 3 and 4; K1542 (disc number); AR9525 (matrix number, side 3), AR9526 (matrix number, side 4). Sides 5 and 6; K1543 (disc number); AR9778 (matrix number, side 5), AR10546 (matrix number, side 6). (Audio 8, Disc 10, Disc 9, Disc 8)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Brandenburgische Konzerte. Nr. 1. Boyd Neel Orchestra; Neel, Boyd, conductor. 1945 June 22; 1945 October 29; 1946 Sept 3.
- Vinyl discs, circa 1926-1957; 55 vinyl discs 54 12" vinyl discs; 1 10" vinyl disc
  - Dvorak, 1956 February; 1 12" vinyl disc; Music For Pleasure, MFP2004. (Audio 8)
    Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Symphonies, no. 9, op. 95, E minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1956 February.
  - Delius, 1947-1954; 1 12" vinyl disc; Philips, G03625L. (Audio 8)
    Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. In a summer garden. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1951 April 3.
    Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Vierge. Dernier sommeil de la Vierge. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 February 9.
    Grétry, André-Ernest-Modeste, 1741-1813. Zémire et Azor. Pantomime. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1954 April 28.